Enter a world of love and enchantment.
Barbie of Swan Lake is a animation, family film directed by Owen Hurley.
Barbie as Odette, the young daughter of a baker, follows a unicorn into the Enchanted Forest and
is transformed into a swan by an evil wizard intent on defeating the Fairy Queen.
Barbie Roberts / Odette (voice), played by Kelly Sheridan.
Prince Daniel (voice), played by Mark Hildreth.
Rothbart (voice), played by Kelsey Grammer.
Odile (voice), played by Maggie Wheeler.
Lila (voice), played by Venus Terzo.
Fairy Queen / Marie (voice), played by Kathleen Barr.
Barbie of Swan Lake is a 2003 animated fantasy film co-produced by Mainframe Entertainment
and Mattel Entertainment, and distributed by Artisan Home Entertainment.
Based on the Tchaikovsky ballet Swan Lake, it is the third in the Barbie film
series, with Kelly Sheridan providing the voice of Barbie.
Barbie of Swan Lake was released on VHS and DVD on September 30, 2003 by Artisan,
later making a television premiere on Nickelodeon on November 16, 2003.
It was subsequently released overseas through
Entertainment Rights and Universal Pictures Video.
The film explores themes of magic, musical, ballet,
based on toy, female protagonist.